What does it mean to spend our time well?
ما الذي يعنيه "أن تقضي وقتك بشكل جيد" ؟
I spend a lot of my time
أنا أُمضي الكثير من وقتي
thinking about how to spend my time.
مُفَكراً كيف أُمضي وقتي.
Probably too much -- I probably obsess over it.
ربما لوقت طويل -- من المحتمل أني مهووس بذلك.
My friends think I do.
أصدقائي يعتقدون أنني كذلك.
But I feel like I kind of have to, because these days,
لكنني أشعر أني مضطر لذلك، لأن هذه الأيام،
it feels like little bits of my time kind of slip away from me,
تبدو كما لو كان الوقت ينفَلِتُ شيئا فشيئا مني،
and when that happens, it feels like parts of my life are slipping away.
وعندما يحدث ذلك، فكأن أجزاء من حياتي تضيع.
Specifically,
خاصةً،
it feels like little bits of my time get slipped away
وأن البعض من وقتي يضيع
to various things like this,
في أشياء متعددة مثل،
like technology -- I check things.
التكنولوجيا -- وأنا أتصفح الأشياء.
I'll give you an example.
سأعطيكم مثالاً.
If this email shows up --
إذا أُرسِلَ لي بريد --
how many of you have gotten an email like this, right?
كم منكم من يحصل على بريد مثل هذا، صحيح؟
I've been tagged in a photo.
أُشيرَ لي في صورة.
When this appears,
عندما يظهر لي هذا،
I can't help but click on it right now.
فلا أتمَهَل، بل أضغط عليها مباشرة.
Right? Because, like, what if it's a bad photo?
صحيح؟ لأن مثلاً ماذا لو أنها صورة سيئة؟
So I have to click it right now.
لذا فعلي أن أضغط عليها مباشرة
But I'm not just going to click "See photo,"
لكن أنا لن أضغط فقط علي زر "رؤية الصورة"
what I'm actually going to do is spend the next 20 minutes.
الذي سأفعله أنني سأضيع الـ 20 دقيقة التالية
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But the worst part is that I know this is what's going to happen,
لكن الأسوأ هو معرفتي أن هذا هو ما سيحدث،
and even knowing that's what's going to happen
وحتى معرفتي بالذي سيحدث
doesn't stop me from doing it again the next time.
لن تمنعني من فعل ذلك في المرة القادمة
Or I find myself in a situation like this,
أو أن أجد نفسي في مَوقِف كهذا
where I check my email and I pull down to refresh,
عندما أتفَقَد بريدي وأسحب للتحديث
But the thing is that 60 seconds later,
لكن الأمر أنني بعد 60 ثانية
I'll pull down to refresh again.
سأسحب مرة أخرى للتحديث من جديد،
Why am I doing this?
لماذا أفعل ذلك؟
This doesn't make any sense.
فهذا بلا معنى،
But I'll give you a hint why this is happening.
لكن سأعطيكم تلميح لسبب حدوث ذلك
What do you think makes more money in the United States
برأيكم ما الذي يُدِر أمولاً في الولايات المتحدة
than movies, game parks and baseball combined?
أكثر من الأفلام، الملاهي وكرة القاعدة معا؟
Slot machines.
أجهزة القمار
How can slot machines make all this money
كيف يمكن لأجهزة القمار أن تَكسِب هذه الأموال
when we play with such small amounts of money?
عندما نلعب بأموال قليلة هكذا؟
We play with coins.
فنحن نلعب بالعملات المعدنية،
How is this possible?
كيف يكون ذلك ممكناً؟
Well, the thing is ...
حسنا، الأمر هو ..
my phone is a slot machine.
أن هاتفي هو جهاز قمار
Every time I check my phone,
في كل مرة أتفَقَد هاتفي،
I'm playing the slot machine to see,
فأنا ألعب القمار لأعرف
what am I going to get?
ما الذي سأحصل عليه؟
Every time I check my email,
في كل مرة أتفَقَد فيها بريدي
I'm playing the slot machine,
أنا ألعب القمار
saying, "What am I going to get?"
متسائلاً "ما الذي سأحصل عليه؟"
Every time I scroll a news feed,
كل مرة أقوم بالتحديث للحصول على أخبار جديدة
I'm playing the slot machine to see,
أنا ألعب بجهاز القمار لأرى
what am I going to get next?
ما الذي سأحصل عليه تالياً؟
And the thing is that,
والشيء هو
again, knowing exactly how this works -- and I'm a designer,
ثانيةً، أنني أعرف كيف يعمل -- فأنا مُصَمم،
I know exactly how the psychology of this works,
وأعلم تماما الأساس النفسِي لعمله،
I know exactly what's going on --
أعلم تماما ما يحصل --
but it doesn't leave me with any choice,
لكنه لا يَدَع لي أي خَيَار
I still just get sucked into it.
لازلت منجذبا إليه،
So what are we going to do?
إذاً ما الذي سنفعله؟
Because it leaves us with this all-or-nothing relationship
لأن هذا يجعلنا في علاقة الكل أو لا شيء
with technology, right?
مع التكنولوجيا، أليس كذلك؟
You're either on,
فإما أن تستخدمها
and you're connected and distracted all the time,
وتكون متَصِل ومُشَتت طوال الوقت،
or you're off,
أو تكون غير متصل
but then you're wondering,
وتظل تتساءل
am I missing something important?
هل يفوتني شيء هام؟
In other words, you're either distracted
بكلمات أخرى أنت إما مُشَتت
or you have fear of missing out.
أو خائف أن يفوتك شيء ما
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
So we need to restore choice.
ولذا علينا أن نستعيد خياراتنا
We want to have a relationship with technology
نحن نريد علاقة مع التكنولوجيا
that gives us back choice about how we spend time with it,
تعطينا الخيار لنتحكم في كيفية قضاء الوقت بإستخدامها،
and we're going to need help from designers,
وسنحتاج مساعدة المصممين
because knowing this stuff doesn't help.
لأن مجرد معرفة ما ذكرته لا يُساعدنا
We're going to need design help.
نحتاج تصميم يساعدنا،
So what would that look like?
إذن ما الذي يبدو عليه ذلك؟
So let's take an example that we all face:
لنأخذ مثلاً نواجهه جميعنا:
chat -- text messaging.
الدردشة -- المراسلات النصية
So let's say there's two people.
لنَقُل أن هناك إثنان من الناس
Nancy's on the left and she's working on a document,
نانسي على اليسار وهي تعمل على مستند ما،
and John's on the right.
وجون على اليمين
And John suddenly remembers,
وجون فجأة تذكر
"I need to ask Nancy for that document before I forget."
"أريد أن أسأل نانسي عن هذا المستند قبل أن أنسى."
So when he sends her that message,
وبهذا عندما يرسل لها تلك الرسالة،
it blows away her attention.
فإنها تخطف إنتباهها.
That's what we're doing all the time, bulldozing each other's attention,
هذا هو ما نفعله طوال الوقت نَجرِف إنتباه بعضنا البعض،
left and right.
يساراً ويميناً.
And there's serious cost to this,
وهناك ثمن غالٍ لهذا،
because every time we interrupt each other,
لأنه في كل مرة نٌقَاطِع بعضنا بعضاً
it takes us about 23 minutes, on average,
نحتاج 23 دقيقة، في المتوسط،
to refocus our attention.
لإعادة تركيزنا.
We actually cycle through two different projects
لأننا ندور بين موضوع مختلفين
before we come back to the original thing we were doing.
قبل أن نعود للشيء الأساسي الذي كنا نقوم به.
This is Gloria Mark's research combined with Microsoft research,
هذا هو بحث جلوريا مارك بالتعاون مع شركة مايكرسوفت للأبحاث،
that showed this.
والذي أظهر هذا.
And her research also shows that it actually trains bad habits.
وأظهر كذلك أن هذا يُرَبي العادات السيئة.
The more interruptions we get externally,
كلما زادت المقاطعات الخارجية،
it's conditioning and training us to interrupt ourselves.
كلما تكيفنا وتعودنا على مقاطعة أنفسنا.
We actually self-interrupt every three-and-a-half minutes.
نحن بالفعل نقاطع أنفسنا كل ثلاث ونصف دقيقة.
This is crazy.
هذا جنون.
So how do we fix this?
إذن كيف يمكننا حَل هذا؟
Because Nancy and John are in this all-or-nothing relationship.
لأن نانسي وجون هما في علاقة الكل أو لاشيء
Nancy might want to disconnect,
نانسي ربما تريد أن تقطع إتصالها
but then she'd be worried:
لكن عندها ستقلق:
What if I'm missing something important?
ماذا لو فاتها شيء مهم؟
Design can fix this problem.
التصميم يمكن أن يَحُل هذه المشكلة.
Let's say you have Nancy again on the left,
لنقل أن لدينا نانسي ثانيةً على اليسار،
John on the right.
وجون على اليمين
And John remembers, "I need to send Nancy that document."
وجون يتذكر "أحتاج أن أرسل لنانسي ذاك المستند."
Except this time,
لكن هذه المرة،
Nancy can mark that she's focused.
نانسي تضع علامة أنها في حالة تركيز.
Let's say she drags a slider and says,
لنقل أنها كتبت في حالتها،
"I want to be focused for 30 minutes,"
"أنا أريد التركيز لمدة 30 دقيقة"
so -- bam -- she's focused.
هكذا -- بام -- تستطيع التركيز.
Now when John wants to message her,
الآن وعندما يَوَد جون أن يرسل لها رسالة،
he can get the thought off of his mind --
قد ينسى الفكرة التي تدور في عقله --
because he has a need, he has this thought,
لأن لديه حاجة، لديه تلك الفكرة،
and he needs to dump it out before he forgets.
الذي يحتاج لقولها قبل أن ينسى.
Except this time,
عدا أنه في هذه المرة،
it holds the messages so that Nancy can still focus,
أوقفت نانسي إستقبال الرسائل ليكون بمقدورها التركيز،
but John can get the thought off of his mind.
لكن جون قد ينسى الفكرة.
But this only works if one last thing is true,
لكن هذا سينجح إذا كان هناك شيء واحد صحيح،
which is that Nancy needs to know that if something is truly important,
وهو أن نانسي تحتاج أن تعرف إذا كان هذا الشيء فعلاً مهم،
John can still interrupt.
ولذا يستطيع جون أن يقاطعها.
But instead of having constant accidental or mindless interruptions,
لكن بدلاً من المقاطعات العارِضَة المستمرة أو التي لا أهمية لها،
we're now only creating conscious interruptions,
نحن بهذا نقاطع بشكل أكثر وعياً،
So we're doing two things here.
وبهذا فنحن نفعل شيئين هنا
We're creating a new choice for both Nancy and John,
نصنع خياراً جديداً بين نانسي وجون،
But there's a second, subtle thing we're doing here, too.
لكن هناك شيء ثانٍ، شيء مهم نفعله هنا، كذلك
And it's that we're changing the question we're answering.
وهو أننا غَيَرنا المشكلة التي نحاول حلَّها.
Instead of the goal of chat being:
فبدلاُ من كون الهدف من برامج الدردشة:
"Let's design it so it's easy to send a message" --
"لنصممه بطريقة تُسَهِل إرسال رسالة" --
that's the goal of chat,
هذا هو هدف برامج الدردشة،
it should be really easy to send a message to someone --
أن يُسَهِل جدا إرسال رسالة لأحدهم --
we change the goal to something deeper and a human value,
غيرنا هدفنا إلى شيء أكثر عُمقا وله قيمة إنسانية،
which is: "Let's create the highest possible quality communication
وهو: "لنصممه بأعلى جودة ممكنة للتواصل
in a relationship between two people.
بين اثنين من الناس.
So we upgraded the goal.
فنحن طورنا الهدف.
Now, do designers actually care about this?
الآن، هل يهتم المصممون فعلاً بهذا؟
Do we want to have conversations about what these deeper human goals are?
هل نريد مناقشة ماهية الأهداف الإنسانية الأكثر عُمقاً؟
Well, I'll tell you one story.
حسناً، سأخبركم قصة ما.
A little over a year ago,
منذ أكثر من سنة مضت،
I got to help organize a meeting
كان عليّ المساعدة في تنظيم إجتماع ما
between some of technology's leading designers and Thich Nhat Hanh.
بين بعض مصممي التكنولوجيا الكِبار و"ثيت نات هَانه".
Thich Nhat Hanh is an international spokesperson for mindfulness meditation.
"ثيت نات هانه" هو متحدث عالمي عن التأمل الذهني.
And it was the most amazing meeting.
وكان هذا أكثر إجتماع مذهل.
You have to imagine -- picture a room --
عليكم أن تتخيلوا -- تخيلوا غرفة --
on one side of the room, you have a bunch of tech geeks;
في أحد جوانبها، لديكم مجموعة من مهووسي التكنولوجيا;
on the other side of the room,
وفي الناحية الأخرى من الغرفة،
you have a bunch of long brown robes, shaved heads, Buddhist monks.
لديكم مجموعة من أَرديَة بُنية طويلة، رؤوس محلوقة، نُسّاك بوذيون.
And the questions were about the deepest human values,
والأسئلة كانت عن القيم الإنسانية الأكثر عُمقا،
like what does the future of technology look like
مثل، ما الذي سيكون عليه مستقبل التكنولوجيا
when you're designing for the deepest questions
إذا قمتم بعمل تصميمات لحل المشاكل الصعبة
and the deepest human values?
ومراعاة القيم الإنسانية المهمة؟
And our conversation centered on listening more deeply
وارتكزت المحادثة على الإستماع بتركيز أكبر
to what those values might be.
لما يمكن أن تعنيه تلك القيم.
He joked in our conversation
مازَحنا أثناء محادثتنا
that what if, instead of a spell check,
لو أننا، بدلاً من "إختبار التهجئة"
you had a compassion check,
كان لدينا "إختبار العاطفة"،
meaning, you might highlight a word that might be accidentally abrasive --
يعني، أنك ربما تُسلط الضوء على كلمة مهينة غير مقصودة --
perceived as abrasive by someone else.
فيعتبرها شخص آخر مهينة.
So does this kind of conversation happen in the real world,
فهل هذا يشبه المحادثة التي تحصل في الواقع،
not just in these design meetings?
ليس فقط في هذه الإجتماعات عن التصميم؟
Well, the answer is yes,
حسناً، الإجابة هي نعم،
and one of my favorites is Couchsurfing.
وواحد من مفضَلاتي هو "كاوتش سيرفينج".
If you didn't know, Couchsurfing is a website
إن كنتم لا تعرفون، كواتش سيرفنج هو موقع على الانترنت
that matches people who are looking for a place to stay
ويَصِل الناس الذين يبحثون عن الإقامة في مكان
with a free couch, from someone who's trying to offer it.
به أريكة شاغرة، بشخص يعرضها.
So, great service --
ولذا، هو يقدم خدمة ممتازة --
what would their design goal be?
ما هو هدفهم في تصميم الموقع؟
What are you designing for if you work at Couchsurfing?
ما الذي ستصممه إن كنت تعمل في موقع كواتش سيرفنج؟
Well, you would think it's to match guests with hosts.
لعلك تفكر في تصميم يَصِل الضيف بالمُضِيف.
Right?
صحيح؟
That's a pretty good goal.
هذا هدف جميل جداً.
But that would kind of be like our goal with messaging before,
لكن هذا مشابه نوعاً ما لهدفنا من المحادثات من قبل،
where we're just trying to deliver a message.
حيث نحاول فقط إيصال رسالة.
So what's the deeper, human goal?
لكن ما الهدف الإنساني الأعمق؟
Well, they set their goal
حسنا، لقد جعلوا هدفهم
as the need to create lasting, positive experiences and relationships
أن يصنعوا تجارب إيجابية دائمة وعلاقات
between people who've never met before.
بين الناس الذين لم يتقابلوا من قبل أبداً
And the most amazing thing about this was in 2007,
وأكثر شئ مذهل في هذا الأمر كان في 2007،
they introduced a way to measure this,
عندما خَلقوا طريقة لقياس هذا،
which is incredible.
والذي كان مذهلاً.
I'll tell you how it works.
سأخبركم كيف فعلوا ذلك.
For every design goal you have,
لكل تصميم لديك هدف،
you have to have a corresponding measurement
سيكون لديك مقياس للتوافق
to know how you're doing --
لتراقب عملك --
a way of measuring success.
طريقة لقياس مدى نجاحك.
So what they do is,
لذا ما فعلوه هو،
let's say you take two people who meet up,
لنقل أن لديك إثنين من الناس يتقابلان،
and they take the number of days those two people spent together,
فهم سجلوا عدد الأيام التي قضاها هذان الإثنان معا،
and then they estimate how many hours were in those days --
وبعد ذلك قاموا بحساب عدد الساعات في تلك الأيام --
how many hours did those two people spend together?
كم عدد الساعات التي قضاها هذان الإثنان معا؟
And then after they spend that time together,
وبعد قضاء هذا الوقت معاً،
they ask both of them:
سألوا كِلَيهما:
How positive was your experience?
ما مدي إيجابية تجربتهما؟
Did you have a good experience with this person that you met?
هل كانت تجربتك جيدة مع الشخص الذي قابلته؟
And they subtract from those positive hours
وقاموا بالطرح من عدد الساعات الإيجابية تلك
the amount of time people spent on the website,
الوقت الذي قضاه الناس على الإنترنت،
because that's a cost to people's lives.
لأن هذا يأخذ من حياة الناس.
Why should we value that as success?
لم نُقَيم هذا على أنه نجاح؟
And what you were left with
ما كنتم بصدده الآن
is something they refer to as "net orchestrated conviviality,"
هو شيء يشيرون إليه على أنه "شبكات العيش المشترك المتناغم"
or, really, just a net "Good Times" created.
أو بالفعل يسمونه فقط شبكة "الأوقات السعيدة".
The net hours that would have never existed, had Couchsurfing not existed.
تلك الساعات التي لم تكن لِتُوجَد، لولا وجود موقع كواتش سيرفنج.
Can you imagine how inspiring it would be to come to work every day
هل بإمكانكم حتى تخيل كم هو مُلهِم أن تذهبوا لعملكم كل يوم
and measure your success
لتُقَيموا نجاحكم
in the actual net new contribution of hours in people's lives
في شبكة واقعية تساهم في خلق أوقات جديدة في حياة الناس
that are positive, that would have never existed
أوقات إيجابية لم تكن لتُوجَد
if you didn't do what you were about to do at work today?
إذا لم تكن تقوم بما تفعله اليوم؟
Can you imagine a whole world that worked this way?
هل يمكنكم تخيل عالم يعمل بنفس الطريقة هذه؟
Can you imagine a social network that --
هل يمكنكم تخيل شبكة إجتماعية --
let's say you care about cooking,
لنَقُل أنك تهتم بالطبخ،
and it measured its success in terms of cooking nights organized
وأن النجاح في مجال الطبخ يُقاس بتنظيم ليالٍ للطبخ
and the cooking articles that you were glad you read,
وطبخ المأكولات التي أعجبتك عند قراءتها،
and subtracted from that the articles you weren't glad you read
وطرح تلك التي لم تعجبك
or the time you spent scrolling that you didn't like?
أو الوقت الذي قضيته وأنت تبحث بين ما لم يعجبك؟
Imagine a professional social network
تخيل شبكة إجتماعية إحترافية
that, instead of measuring its success in terms of connections created
التي وبدلاً من قياس نجاحها على أساس الإتصال
or messages sent,
أو إرسال رسالة
instead measured its success in terms of the job offers that people got
بدلاً من قياس نجاحها على أساس الوظائف التي توفرها للناس
that they were excited to get.
التي كانت موجودة قبلاً بوفرة
And subtracted the amount of time people spent on the website.
و اطرح الوقت الذي يُمضيه الناس على الموقع.
Or imagine dating services,
أو تخيل مواقع البحث عن شريك،
like maybe Tinder or something,
مثل (تيندر) أو ما شابه،
where instead of measuring the number of swipes left and right people did,
حيث بدلاً من حساب مرات مرور الناس على ملفك الشخصي يمينا ويساراً،
which is how they measure success today,
والتي هي طريقة قياس النجاح اليوم،
instead measured the deep, romantic, fulfilling connections people created.
بدلاً من ذلك نقيم النجاح بالعلاقات الرومانسية العميقة المُرضية بين الناس
Whatever that was for them, by the way.
أياً كان ما يريدونه.
But can you imagine a whole world that worked this way,
لكن هل بإمكانكم تخيل عالم كامل يعمل بتلك الطريقة،
that was helping you spend your time well?
يساعدكم في قضاء أوقاتكم بشكل أمثَل؟
Now to do this you also need a new system,
الآن لنفعل ذلك نحتاج لنظام جديد،
because you're probably thinking,
لأنكم ربما تفكرون
today's Internet economy --
أن إقتصاد الإنترنت حالياً --
today's economy in general --
الإقتصاد كَكُل حالياً --
is measured in time spent.
يُقَيَم بالوقت الذي نقضيه.
The more users you have,
كلما زاد عدد المستخدمين،
the more usage you have,
كلما زاد الإستخدام،
the more time people spend,
كلما قضى الناس وقتاً أطول،
that's how we measure success.
بهذه الطريقة نقيس النجاح حالياً.
But we've solved this problem before.
لكن نحن حللنا هذه المشكلة قبلاً.
We solved it with organic,
حللناها بالمواد العضوية،
when we said we need to value things a different way.
عندما قررنا أننا نحتاج لتقييم الأشياء بطريقة مختلفة.
We said this is a different kind of food.
قُلنا أن هذا نوع مختلف من الطعام.
So we can't compare it just based on price;
وبهذا لا يمكن مقارنته فقط على أساس السعر;
this is a different category of food.
أصبح لدينا تصنيف مختلف للطعام.
We solved it with Leed Certification,
حللناها بـ "شهادة ليد" ( في الهندسة الصديقة للبيئة)
where we said this is a different kind of building
عندما قُلنا هذا نوع مختلف من المباني
that stood for different values of environmental sustainability.
على أساس معايير الحفاظ على البيئة.
What if we had something like that for technology?
ماذا لو أصبح لدينا شيء مماثل في التكنولوجيا؟
whose entire purpose and goal
ماذا لو لدينا شيء الغرض والهدف منه
was to help create net new positive contributions to human life?
هو مساعدة الناس لخَلق صِلات جديدة إيجابية في حياة الإنسان؟
And what if we could value it a different way,
وماذا لو اختلفت طريقة تقييمنا للأشياء،
so it would actually work?
لتعطي الثمرة المرجوة؟
Imagine you gave this different premium shelf space on app stores.
تخيل أنك أعطيت المساحات مدفوعة الثمن في متجر التطبيقات.
Imagine you had web browsers that helped route you
تخيل لو أصبح لديك المتصفح الذي يساعدك علي الوصول
to these kinds of design products.
لكل أنواع التطبيقات.
Can you imagine how exciting it would be to live and create that world?
هل بإمكانك تصور كم هو مثير إنشاء هذا العالم والعيش فيه؟
We can create this world today.
بإمكاننا إنشاء هذا العالم اليوم.
Company leaders, all you have to do --
يا رؤساء الشركات، كل ما عليكم فعله --
only you can prioritize a new metric,
تستطيعون إعطاء الأولوية لمعايير جديدة،
which is your metric for net positive contribution to human life.
تكون معايير لشبكة للتواصل بإيجابية بين الناس.
And have an honest conversation about that.
قوموا بعمل مناقشات صادقة عن هذا الأمر.
Maybe you're not doing so well to start with,
ربما لن تكون البداية واعدة،
but let's start that conversation.
لكن لنبدأ تلك النقاشات.
Designers, you can redefine success; you can redefine design.
المصممين بإمكانكم إعادة تعريف النجاح; بإمكانكم إعادة تعريف التصميم.
Arguably, you have more power than many people in your organization
جدلياً لديكم سلطة أكبر من غيركم في مؤسساتِكم
to create the choices that all of us live by.
لخلق خيارات نعتمد عليها في حياتنا.
Maybe like in medicine,
ربما مثل الطب،
where we have a Hippocratic oath
حيث لدينا "قَسَم أبقراط"
to recognize the responsibility and this higher value
لتَقدير المسئولية والقِيَم العُليا
that we have to treat patients.
التي لدينا لعلاج المرضى.
What if designers had something like that,
ماذا لو أصبح لدى المصممين شيء كهذا،
in terms of this new kind of design?
من أجل إيجاد نوع جديد من التصميم؟
And users, for all of us --
والمستخدمين، لنا جميعا أقول --
we can demand technology that works this way.
نستطيع أن نطلب تكنولوجيا تعمل بهذه الطريقة.
Now it may seem hard,
ربما يبدو الأمر صعباً حالياً،
but McDonald's didn't have salads until the consumer demand was there.
لكن في "ماكدونلدز" لم يُقَدِموا السلطة حتى طلبها المستهلكون.
Walmart didn't have organic food
"والمرت" لم يكن لديهم طعام عضوي حتى طلبه المستهلكون منهم.
We have to demand this new kind of technology.
علينا أن نُطالِب بهذا النوع الجديد من التكنولوجيا.
And we can do that.
وبإمكاننا فِعل ذلك.
And doing that
وبفعل ذلك
would amount to shifting from a world that's driven and run
بإمكاننا تغيير مسار العالم القائم على
entirely on time spent,
الإعتماد على قضاء الوقت،
to world that's driven by time well spent.
إلى عالم يقضي الوقت بشكل جيد.
I want to live in this world,
أريد أن أحيا في هذا العالم،
and I want this conversation to happen.
وأريد أن نتناقش عن هذا الأمر.
Let's start that conversation now.
ولنبدأ نقاشنا من الآن.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)